Mohan Prasad

Phone: (M) +91-9652957279, Email: dev.mohanj2ee@hotmail.com; dev.mohanj2ee@gmail.com

Having 12 years of experience in Java/J2ee technologies and currently working as Java Full Stack Lead Developer in Brillio Technologies Pvt Ltd, Pune and having very strong concept in web application development using Java/J2EE,SpringBoot technologies with Angular/ReactJS and NodeJS

- Extensive experience in implementing applications with Model/View/Controller (MVC) design pattern.
- Proficient in Developing Middleware applications, Web Applications, Client/Server.
- Extensive experience in application development using Java, J2EE, Spring/Spring Boot MS,
 Angular, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, NodeJS and AWS Cloud infrastructure.
- Extensive experience in TDD using Junit, Mockito and Power Mockito frameworks.
- Experience in Technical Architect for High level System design.
- Good exposure at each stage of SDLC (Analysis, Design, Development & Testing).
- Extensive experience in Scrum/Agile Methodology.
- Proficient in using Tools like Eclipse, IntelliJ, Web Storm, VS Code, Subline Text
- Effective communication, team building & relationship management skills.
- Dedicated and highly ambitious to achieve personal goals as well as the organizational goals.
- Interacting with the client for technical specifications, changes, and deliverable.

Experience Summary

Brillio Technology Pvt Ltd. (Senior-Lead Engineer)-Pune
 Capgemini Technology Service Pvt Ltd. (Senior-Consultant)-Mumbai
 Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd. (Senior Software Engineer)-Mumbai
 Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. (Systems Engineer)-Hyderabad
 Birlasoft (India) Limited. (Software Engineer)-Hyderabad
 June 2012 - March 2015
 June 2012 - March 2015

Technical Skills

Framework : Angular, ReactJS, Spring Boot, Hibernate

Database : Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSql,DB2,MongoDB

Application/Web Server : JBossAS, Jetty, Tomcat

Software Tools : JIRA, Confluence, Rally, TDP

Version Control Tools : SVN, GitHub, Bitbucket

Build Tool : Ant, Maven, Gradle

Cloud Services : AWS CloudFront, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy

CloudFormation,S3,DynamoDB,API Gateway,RDS,Docker and K8s

Domain Experience

- e-Commerce
- Energy and Utilities (Oil & gas)
- Health & Public Service(H&PS)
- Telecommunication (Telecom)
- Banking and Financial Services(BFS)

Educational Qualification

- Master of Computer Applications from VTU University, Belgaum 2010
- Bachelor of Science from Vinoba Bhave University, Hazaribagh 2006
- 10+2 from Jharkhand Intermediate Council, Ranchi 2002
- 10th from Bihar School Examination Board, Patna 2000

Project Details

Project #1 Bulletin e-commerce Application

Client Emerald

Duration March 2024 – till date

Technologies JDK17, Python, NodeJS PostgreSQL, Angular, React, SpringBoot, AWS

Tool Used IntelliJ, Postman, GitHub, Serverless framework, AWS Services, DataDog, Algolia

Project Description

Bulletin Marketplace is a curated wholesale marketplace for premium e commerce community where retailers and Brands user can discover, meet, and shop the best brands on the planet.

Responsibilities

- Improved Performance for Shopify-import python application
- Improved Performance for Csv-importer python application
- Upgrade Java8 to Java17 in Bulletin Spring Boot Backend Application
- Unit Testing in Spring boot and Python application

Developed Lambda function with layer capabilities using Python and deployed via Serverless framework in AWS cloud.

Project #2 Reece e-commerce Application

Client Reece

Duration June 2022 – March 2024

Technologies JDK11, PostgreSQL, ReactJS, CloudFormation, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFront, CDK,AWS

Lambda, Docker, k8s, Apigateway

Tool Used IntelliJ, AWS Cloud, IBM Acoustic CMS

Project Description

Reece Group is a leading distributor of plumbing, waterworks and HVAC-R products to commercial and residential customers through over 800 branches in Australia, New

Zealand and the United States

Responsibilities

• Migrated around 200 bitbuckets repo to github with github Action CI/CD pipeline.

• Developed PLP and PDP backend service.

• Developed stencil and react js web components for Reece frontend.

· Maintained and developed front pages on Acoustic CMS

Developed Lambda function using NodeJS and deployed vis AWS cloud formation

Project #3 Energy Real Time(ETR)

Client GRTgaz, France

Duration Sep 2019– April 2022

Technologies JDK8, Multithreading, Oracle11g, Angular JS/Angular10, Typescript, ReactJS and

JavaScript, ActiveMQ, Rest Easy, MyBatis, EhCache with SAG Terracotta Big Memory,

Swagger, SAG webMethod, SpringBoot Microservice, Docker and K8s on WAS

Tool Used SVN, JIRA, JbossAS7/WildFly, Eclipse, Web Storm, VS Code, AWS Cloud, Maven, SAG

WebMethod, Ehcache, MyBatis, SAG Big Memory Terracotta and JMeter

Project Description ETR-Simone application is a Web based Applications of GRTGaz (Natural Gas

transmission, France) which is used across its organization to manage the metering of Gas

data. It mainly targets to calculate the Energy that is transmitted by the business to its end

users.

GRTGaz is mainly into transmissions and ETR play a critical role which gives LIVE Metering data that is coming from each node – PCE/ FGAs. They basically provide the

GCV that is used for calculating the Energy in the system.

Project #4 Garda Information Bureau System(GIBS)

Client Irish Police (SIRENE Bureau), Government of Ireland

Duration June 2015– September 2019

Technologies JDK8, SOAP, SOAP UI, Oracle11g, Angular2/4/5, ES5/6, Typescript, and JavaScript,

Atomikos, RabbitMQ, Lombock,

Spring (REST, JPA, Hibernate, IOC, AOP, Spring Boot), JMS, AWS, DevOps

Tool Used GIT, Gerrit, JIRA, JbossAS7, Eclipse, Web Storm, VS Code, AWS Cloud, Maven

Project Description

GIBS is a part of the Schengen Information System II (SIS II) Project for A Garda Síochána. And will support the A Garda Síochána (AGS) in the management of Case Files and the sharing of information with other member states as part of the operational function of SIS II and enable users within the AGS to create, manage and exchange information on

Case Files.

Key modules used in GIBS are GIBS Inbox, Case File Details (CFD), Case File Management (CFM), and common modules of GPP will be same Dashboard, Search, Reporting, admin and Audit.

Responsibilities

- Gathering requirement from client
- Prepare design document.
- Individual contributor for CFD and CFM
- Worked as Full Stack developer (Frond end and backend developer)
- Unit testing for Java and Angular2
- Worked as a Module Lead for CFD/CFM.

Achievements

List all the professional and unprofessional achievements or the awards received during the tenure.

- AWS Certified Developer Associate at Brillio in 2023
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate at Brillio in 2024
- Awarded as the Cappemini Start award for Q4 2019.
- Awarded as the Accenture ACE award for Q4 2017
- Awarded as the Birla soft Star Team for Q3 2014
- Appreciated multiple times by business users for my quick resolution to complex issues & business critical Production Bugs Resolution.

Personal Details

Name : Mohan Prasad
Date of birth : 15th Oct, 1984
Status : Married

E-Mail : dev.mohanj2ee@gmail.com

Mohan Prasad